the past being having a
gravity right of the historicity
of that's like not history like
you know a series of events that are
available to everybody
right but history in the sense of the
way that you and i
are sitting that it makes sense to sit
in the way that we
are that we're on a chair that were
upright that were
that you went like this that if that
there's a
like that all that has intelligibility
is layered
in gravities yeah of
customs of social practices of cultures
of
that we live right yet
that history is in some sense
the big is the history of the constant
becoming
of the future right the calling is
forward
right and so the present is that point
where it's it goes
future past and then the present is the
mutuality of those points where it goes
it comes into comes into like music like
with music you only hear
you pick up the note but actually the
note animates the tensions of the
like the elongating rhythms of the past
and then the
the anticipation of the future is what
you
is the experience of the music it's not
the
animated note of the present
so that sense of richness um and when
you said
uh-huh can i say something oh please
i had a i had an experience with a
a gentleman named josh who's a truly
masterful
guitar player like capital m
um and we were in we were in an
ayahuasca ceremony
and he was playing music as part of it
and he wasn't playing songs he was
playing music
which is to say that every note that was
struck was new
in the universe in the relationship of
the context that it was in
had never been played before and would
never be played again
and i listened very closely for a while
for like an hour two hours i don't know
how long it was
as you can imagine um he did not strike
a single false note
he played continuously for hours and
every note was
perfectly placed between the note before
and after and had never been played
before he was not playing a song but
rather he was
creating music yeah that i think is
that's a very nice way of
of speaking to this yeah totally
totally that's that also really
highlights that notion of concealment
yeah if i if i whistle the tune of
beethoven's ninth symphony
there's something very very different
very different about that
yeah not the same yeah that's the past
right that's the past reanimating itself
through me
as opposed to the future revealing
itself through me
well in some way in some way it's just
it's like the past is already a reach
it's in it's always and it seems to me
that
the past only shows up in its
bringing gravity to the nurturing forth
of a possibility
right um i like that it sounds really
nice
yeah this kind of weaving sense of it
and i i think this is but my experience
of
of that most of the things that i call
genui like genuinely good in my life
have started with the sense of i'm going
along
and then something shines forth right
and then i'm like and i just
if i'm fortunate enough i could just
can't stop looking at it right and then
start moving in that direction
but the things that have been really
deep for me have been
this process of like 20 years later
i'm still finding out what i was
interested in
right and then the the trail that's left
behind is like our like
methodologies and religions and like a
whole
series of things of me finding out what
i was interested in
right or what grabbed or seized me
um and this is the this is the mystery
to me of like i don't actually
understand how do i
know to be struck by something
before i understand it to be struck by
it
yeah i mean that's uh such a it is a
mystery in fact it may be the mystery
we may find ourselves dancing around the
the light of religion on that exact note
yeah
um i've had the same exact experience
yeah in fact the way you were describing
uh heidegger made me laugh because i had
the feeling with uh with deloitte
where i'm sitting there and i have this
feeling of just like almost being like
held and like smacked up against it
you know for years just boom boom and uh
you know just cracking open uh the
anti-oedipus and just reading through
the whole thing and going
i don't know what the just happened
like i had i don't even
recall a single word that was said what
the what's going on and then i would
read and read and read and just like
as you say like it's it's like this
absorption this this digestion this
metabolism
what is it what is it that
brings you into that and and locks you
into it like does it make sense why in
god's name would you spend that much
time
yeah doing something that you can't
justify
you cannot it does not make sense the
whole point is it doesn't make sense and
yet
it is the very center of that which is
uh well shoot i was i stopped myself
from speaking because something else
popped in
um one of the things i've noticed and we
could even say two have become wise
wisdom so as i've gotten older wisdom
for me is precisely the ability to have
had enough of those experiences
to say ah it's another one of those
again okay
all right you know i've been through
i've seen you before i'm quite certain
that i have the slightest idea what's
going on here and that's okay
because everything that's really
mattered has been like this
so i'm gonna stick with this yes so
there's a way
there's a there's a is it is it fair to
say that well i think what you just said
is
there's a way that i could come to know
that not knowing
to where i'm
my character becomes shaped into someone
that can
not know more
that yeah yeah that that right there yes
[Laughter]
i just felt like two monkeys for a
moment
which you can imagine right yeah this is
the same thing we're actually doing the
same thing like
the first monkey like napped the flint
yeah the other was like yes
yes whatever whatever you just did there
dude that was it i don't know what
whoa can we do that again